Cambridge, MA 02141 201.669.1680 j.skrable@gmail.com

Talented and innovative data engineer with six years of professional experience building and consuming REST APIs and ETL processes. In my current role, I quickly mastered the industry leading SnapLogic integration platform for use by clients across BU, one of the largest private universities in the world. I continually work to design, optimize, implement, and improve processes using novel technology. I learn rapidly, think broadly, and develop with attention to detail.

Professional Experience

Boston University Information Services & Technology

Boston, MA

Programmer Analyst III

Feb 2020 - Present

- Engineered a JSON schema validator to check referential integrity, build dereferenced schema files, and display an interactive visual representation of the schemas on a static site. Uses Node.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, JSDOM, AWS S3.
- Architected and developed an API service to collect data about university-affiliated persons from various sources, validate the data, and coalesce into a master person record for organization-wide consumption. Serves 100,000+ calls per day.
- Implemented API service to collect course catalog data from data warehouse for consumption by clients across university.
- Designed and developed a generic REST API service to publish and consume messages. Uses AWS SQS and SNS.

Programmer Analyst II

July 2018 – Feb 2020

- Created a generic integration logging pipeline and designed a common logging data model to collect, analyze, and distribute integration run logs among stakeholders, saving time and promoting interaction between departments. Uses JS and JSON.
- Developed REST APIs for university research cloud migration, using JavaScript, JSON, Active Directory, and PostgreSQL
- Led team of developers to implement a self-service portal using for university integration consumers. Hosted as static site on AWS; automated deployment using a continuous integration pipeline. Built with JavaScript, Bootstrap, S3, and Lambda
- Developed an integration to move resume data from complex type XML to JSON to SQL server DB using JavaScript and Python within SnapLogic. Modularized into REST APIs to allow for consumption across the university as a microservice.

Programmer Analyst I

April 2017 – July 2018

- Organized and developed integration to move complex college applicant data from mainframe to Salesforce using JSON and JavaScript within SnapLogic. Architected a canonical data model and maintained throughout process.
- Architected and implemented reporting database for integrations, consolidating multiple platforms. Uses AWS Aurora.
- Designed and created generalized file transport platform for use across the university. Uses AWS Aurora and JavaScript.

WGBH Educational Foundation

Boston, MA

Senior Support and Data Analyst

Nov 2016 - March 2017

- Developed method to capture subscriptions from web forms, leverage donor matching process, and transmit to Salesforce using RESTful Web Services to distribute marketing data among employees and increase overall donor engagement
- Implemented automated sync process between Salesforce and data warehouse using mix of web services and ETL tools
- Orchestrated full SQL Server database implementation, including architecture, tuning, software, and roles install.

Support and Data Analyst

Jan 2015 - Nov 2016

- Provided prompt and thorough technical support for WGBH and external stations' donor database platform, focused on
 efficient and accurate communication between Salesforce front-end and SQL Server data warehouse
- Performed full database conversions from various client sources (Oracle, MySQL) into Salesforce
- Enhanced and refined heuristic matching operations for incoming and existing accounts, contacts, and leads

Technologies

Python, Javascript, Node.js, Java, C, PySpark, TensorFlow, Keras, sk-learn, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Flask, JQuery, Bootstrap, MVC, HTML, CSS, REST, SOAP, Linux, Bash, zsh, Windows, Git, *SQL, S3, Aurora, Lambda, API Gateway, SNS, SQS, SnapLogic, Salesforce

Education

Boston University

Master of Science in Computer Science, GPA 3.97

Sep 2017 – Jan 2020

Projects: Music Recommendation Using Deep Learning Neural Network, Traveling Salesman Solution Using Simulated Annealing, RSA and El Gamal Cryptography, Genetic Algorithm to Mimic Fish Schooling Behavior, Sarcasm Detection in Headlines Using PySpark

Boston University

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, Information Systems and Entrepreneurship

Sep 2010 - May 2014